

Anthony Poluch

Business Intelligence Analyst

Cell: (484) 866-7744 | Email: anthonypoluch@gmail.com

ABOUT

I specialize in data sourcing, processing, and visualization to deliver actionable insights. I am dedicated to continuously learning additional data science tools to enhances my existing skill set and expand my knowledge of the ever-evolving field of data science.

EDUCATION

University of Pittsburgh
BS- Business Administration
Business Information Systems,
Supply Chain Management
Marketing

SKILLS

Tableau VBA

Alteryx Power Bl

Python Excel

SQL Tableau Prep

R HTML

CERTIFICATIONS

Tableau Desktop Certified Associate Alteryx Designer Core Certification Lean Six Sigma Yellow Belt

PORTFOLIO WEBSITE



WORK EXPERIENCE

AWS, Business Intelligence Analyst

October 2022 - Present

- Answered strategic business questions and provide actionable intelligence through the design and creation of data pipelines using SQL, Tableau Prep, etc. to generate dataset which I used to create visualizations providing an easy way to digest and understand the data
- Tools: DataGrip, SQL, PyCharm, python, Tableau, Tableau Prep,

Highmark Health, Senior Business Intelligence Analyst May 2022 - October 2022

- Assisted in the implementation of Oracle Analytics Cloud by setting up and defining the contents of its data housed in the ADW
- Became a SME in Oracle Analytics Cloud and helped define and build new data sources to be used in the tool
- Built management dashboards providing insight into financial operations
- Tools: Oracle Analytics Cloud, Oracle OTBI, Excel, Alteryx, PowerBI

Highmark Health, Senior Data Reporting Analyst

June 2021 - May 2022

- Assisted in the implementation of Oracle ERP by setting up its reporting tool and provided training and support to end users
- Lead the adoption effort of the Oracle Analytics Cloud and built out ETL processes to source and visualize data used by leadership
- Tools: Oracle OTBI, Oracle Analytics Cloud, Excel, PowerBI

Highmark Health, Data Reporting Analyst

June 2020 - June 2021

- Use Tableau as a front-end BI tool and Alteryx as a back end data sourcing, processing, and automation tool to design and develop workflows, dashboards, and self-service data
- Tools: Tableau, Alteryx, Python, Excel

Highmark Health, Emerging Leaders Program Associate

June 2018 - June 2020

Rotational program consisting of four 6-month rotations in various data analyst

- Developed and automated data sourcing, cleaning, and processing infrastructure using Alteryx and Toad for Oracle for team's data needs
- Developed Tableau dashboards visualizing resource forecasted time data, resource availability, resource skills data, and financial and utilization data
- Tools: Alteryx, Tableau, Toad, Power BI, SQL, Excel, VBA, Cognos